That 3. So good morning, everyone. Uh, I think
due to our canvas, um, breakdown and then
And uh actually, the course material were uploaded uh
on Saturday. So you should be able to see all the stuff in
our website. However, I also realized there's
no preview can be obtained if you click those.
Maybe because some functionality were affected after this
breakdown. And if you see that one here,
um, you can download, OK, you can download and you can open that
one to, speak the preview
or the leading or and update the links, um.
In the learning activity. But just in the slides,
I don't think you can preview, but you can definitely download,
OK? Um, and this one should work as well.
So, yes, so, yeah, so this question from,
from this class, uh, yeah, so, Kevin, so yeah,
uh, hopefully everyone can, can find it,
it is working properly right now. OK.
Um, so today, our comment is about the 4.2.
Uh, as I said, we have 4.1, 4.2, and 4.3,
and then the course is done. OK? So all these three week study
around policy and the people, right? And uh,
as we said, all these three parts are equally important.
Although we focused most of our time in technology,
um, but It doesn't mean it's more important than people because
we found if we read the cyber incident report,
you would say, oh, the people are actually the main cause and even caused
more than 80% of incidents which were because people's error,
human error. Which is why we, we have to focus on
human aspect in this week. OK, we'll talk about social engineering and why the
bad people can always trick trick good people to do the bad things,
right? So we'll talk about those psychological influence and to talk about that
one. And I'll also will list some social engineering techniques that people
are using to, to, um, To
get through the system, OK, via people, right?
And then we will, we will talk about the cyberwareness improvement.
Mobile device, internet use, and I'll cover the two aspects
because these are the main parts and people are interacting every
day, right? So, what are the awareness we should have,
right? OK. So, And then here, I just use this
one as one example, um, just show you how many of them were caused
by a human being, right? All this shape,
jaded color uh because of people. Either it's an employee
or careless employee or the three-party contractor that all through people,
OK? They will happen. They will happen. And then with this um
notifiable data breaches report, Um, maintained
by Australian government. And if you go to the link,
you should be able to see, unfortunately,
they haven't uploaded their 2025 reports.
And what you can see is the first, yeah,
the latest one is the second half of 2024 years
report. Right? When you, this is a report,
um, yeah, I, I'm reading now. And you can see that these are how
many uh notification which have been
there. It should be the newest one.
Yeah, this one only gives this data, right?
So, which is, uh, which is the newest one.
OK. And then you can see the top 5 sector,
we have all this sector, um, In those data breaches.
So, the most uh uh affected one is the health and the government and
finance, and then legal, accounting and management services and then
retail, right? And then if we look at the cyber incidents,
and you can see how many of them are caused by phishing and then by ransomware,
by compromised uh or stolen credentials.
And all this one actually involves human,
humans mistakes. Right? And then, of course,
with the brute force attack, compromise the credential,
if human can have enough awareness and make sure they have set up their password
properly and also turn on their second factor
authentication, and then the brute force attack wouldn't work,
right? So we are, we now know that, right?
So, and And basically, human error breaches,
um, you can see that top calls can be unauthorized
disclosure or the emails sent to the wrong people and the failure to
BCC, uh, use, uh, failure to use BCC. So,
these are just the human's, uh, mistakes,
right? So, from the report, I can see how human
are vulnerable in this cyberspace, right?
And we've got to make sure as a, like this
course student, and we got to understand what are the social engineering techniques
that people are using and then how human should prevent
those, right? And then this is just the one
category. Uh, you can see all these different names.
I'll probably walk through very many different names today.
And then just let you aware and then we have this many
different things, OK, in this um domain relevant to people.
And firstly, about fishing, spear fishing,
and wing, um, so normally the phishing, uh,
they're all similar. Just trick people to believing something,
right? So those phishing email, um, it's just,
uh, um, like fishing used to target to any,
anyone. And spear fishing target certain employees,
such as HR officer or finance officer. And willing to
target more higher employees, right? So with the phishing email,
and there are some key indicators, uh, such as
the Salutation here is very vague
and the suspicious domain here, right? The company,
uh, if we have, uh, like, oh, the domain here as well,
right? So when you see that email domain,
that's not Bank of America's domain. And this link,
if we hover over the link, and we probably see a different URL linked,
uh which looks like a Bank of America, but which is actually not.
And we can also see awkward grammar in here,
and then we see some urgent Uh, with this
one, it doesn't have any urgent title, but sometimes we see that
urgent and warning, intimidating phrases,
um, included in that, in that subject, and we should be aware that might be just a
phishing email. And then no legitimate contact information at the
end. And there's a spoofed the logo and header,
OK, like this, right? So, we just have to uh be aware of this key
indicator and then we know that might be very likely to be a phishing
email. And then there are variation from fishing,
such as smashing, fishing, and watering hole attacks.
OK. The smishing and fishing are just very easy to understand.
And then that watering hole attacks, uh,
which is different from the fishing. The fishing is kind of
giving you some allure, lure, right? So that you,
um, be tricked to do something. And then,
however, the watering hole attack is to,
more like um, uh, we poison the whole water
pool and then just wait until
another person to come to the place and then get the water and then get poisoned.
So that's a watering hole attacks. With that watering hole attack
can happen online such as uh we
compromise a web server and then we know the website
uh maintained by that server, right, will be used by a
special group of people, uh, which can be their members
or can be, um, uh, certain, any, yeah,
certain group of people, right? So, you,
you can imagine if you have a conference and then only um the
conference register, uh who have registered the conference,
um, and then those people would go to the conference and pay the money to
register the conference, right? And then only those members who are paying
will be attacked. And it's very hard to identify um this
kind of watering hole attacks through traffic analysis because there
is no abnormal traffic pattern in this
internet, right? So, that's why we call this,
this is hard to identify. Um, but, We just have to maintain
the website clean, as clean as possible,
so that there's no watering hole attack to our users,
right? So, what to do, of course, we, uh,
we wish Uh, you won't be targeted. So that
when you're using your social media and you're not oversharing,
and you also don't use your social media,
don't visit your social media site on your,
um, com company equipments, right? Cause sometimes when you visit
your social media using your, your, uh, company equipments,
then, uh, you might, you might. Get attacked
through this watering hole attack. Because the social media site can be
something which will not maintained very well,
and the bad people can just put some bad links
to some advertisements through those social media sites.
And then once you click those links, and you will get hacked.
Your computer can have problem, right? So because the watering hole attacks
can happen to those social media sites. They target at you and then they know you are a
member of that social media site and, and then they would just
poison the whole site. OK, like this, put the water,
put a poison to the water, right? And then,
um, So we should not oversharing because that can
help bad people to identify those targeted
specific group of people. And then know you work and you have a particular kind
of work. And if you're sharing your business activity,
and you attend a conference through the social media,
and then they wanted you to click something
in that website of that, of that conference,
so then they can just try to find the vulnerability in that conference website,
right? And then, yeah, through that way,
and then the watering hole attack can, can just uh Um,
reach you, your computer, right? OK.
So, these are the way not to, um, yeah, not
get targeted. And then there's a name for tail
tailgating and piggybacking, OK, piggybacking,
right? So, of course, uh, we should say no tailgating,
no piggybacking. And the difference between these two is tailgating in the first
person doesn't, uh, uh, is not aware there's people behind him.
But, and then the piggybacking means the first one,
consciously carry the second person to go through the security door,
right? And then, so, these are the tailgating and the
piggybacking difference. And then with the main trap configuration,
basically mean we have a double door and then the first door allow
Uh, multiple people to get through. And second door,
just, uh, one person can get through. So,
those tailgated people and piggybackbacked people,
and then they will be trapped between two doors.
So we said the main trap configuration uh can be very
effectively uh uh uh applied, deployed here.
So, yeah, so, of course, we wish there's,
uh, yeah, the tailgating and the piggybacking can be addressed by some,
um, the security, um, Physical security
when like some kind of policy right there.
And then shimming, uh, shimming is a stealing money from the card,
right? So it can happen through all this ATM or gas station,
the community store, and so on. So you call that shimming because there's a special name there.
And impersonation means, um, a
person impersonate another one and then just want to get through,
um, some building or sometimes get access to a special
resources, right? So, um, it can happen
physically, it can also happen online, right?
So we saw a lot of impersonations or spoofing happening,
right? And then, So through online behavior and then finally,
the, the, they got access or they got some information,
they gathered some information and then they can now um do that one in
person, physically. So, that's what impersonate
impersonation normally happen, right? And then,
they, they, with this, if, for example, they,
they, they, they do some spoofing and then they check some image,
email, and they found you're expecting a
fire inspection on Monday. And then there's a person
with a fire um suits, OK? Right? And then coming to
inspect. And then, and then you saw that uh official person
sent from the, from the office. However,
it, it may not be the right one, right? So,
so that's an impersonation. And then they can be through many
different, um, different ways, right? Like penetration
tester, and new hired employees, and so on,
right? All these different types of impersonation can happen,
uh, in reality. And, and there's also dumpster diving.
Uh the name here means a person can um just
collect useful information from the rubbish bin.
OK, very easy concepts here. But what, what can be
um stolen from the rubbish bin can uh include all these
things, OK? Um, there's some of them are very valuable information for bad
people, such as the, uh, IP addresses, maybe some invoices,
and then they know what products you are buying,
right, uh, ordered from, for your company.
And then they impersonate first as the pest control or as a
cleaner, and then they do dumpster diving later and then try to collect or
gather all the information from you, right?
So these are what happening here and then the,
the, all these different behavior are linked together,
uh, maybe to launch some uh later very uh relevant phishing
email to you and then you saw those are very,
very relevant to your life and then, uh,
there's a, um, this must be a real email
or real request and then you just, uh, um,
handle that quickly. But, but those bad people,
they have done through this impersonation,
dumpster diving, and then they have done a lot,
a lot of analysis on your, um, daily duty.
And then, and then they send you a phishing email and then you tend to believe that's true,
right? So, You know, there are some events you're organizing,
and then maybe there's some invoice you have to pay,
and then, and then they would probably invoice you as a finance officer and then you just
thought that if you're not aware of not have very like high
awareness in this kind of space, and you probably just
tend to believe that that email invoice is correct,
and you just pay that. It is that very bad thing can happen in this way,
right? So all these are linked. And then the shooter surfing and very
easy concepts here. Um, so all these are examples of
shoulder surfing and then a very interesting thing to know here is
that there are some high-tech glasses, right,
which can actually, um, memory, memorize a lot of stuff
or sending those information online, right?
And, and then just to do this through this,
through the surfing. And then there's also a name called USB key dropping,
or sometimes we call that dead dropping.
With this one, those USB key are malicious,
right? They can be available in gift package or in some foyer and
some conference center, right? And then maybe some people deliberately just uh
drop that there and then next day, other people can get
them. And then normally when you pick up one USB,
probably what, what most people would do is to go home and plug into your
computer and check what's inside. If it's a very big one,
like, Uh, 128 gigabytes and you think, oh you,
you got something useful. And however, what you don't know
is that USB can be um something um
attached by a malicious software, right?
And then your computer would be probably installed as spyware,
and some people can do a remote spy on your computer and so on.
So, all these things can happen, right? So,
just be aware when we, when we got some USB lost somewhere
by other people, don't just plug into your own computer.
OK. Even with those uh gift package one,
Yeah, we got to make sure there's nothing bad in that USB.
If you have the updated antivirus software,
just scan them first, right? Um, yeah, do not just trust that
that's uh, uh, innocent USB and dropped by another person.
OK? And then there's a hoaxing online. So,
the hoaxing, um, Probably you have been hoaxed before,
right? And when you receive a message, ask you to spread to 5 of
your friends, and then you will get a good fortune and that kind of
um thing is an example of hoaxing, right?
And sometimes it also can, this is just one example here.
It can also, um, sometimes you receive some fake
news and the fake warning of virus. OK,
those can all be an example of hoaxing. OK.
And then, this is a very famous six persuasion
principles, OK, um, found by Robert,
um, In 2007, and which has been used in
many different domains. OK. It, if you are in the
business domain, you probably have heard this one.
And if you're learning some marketing rule,
um, or if you are a sales, and then you actually,
this rule have been used by those people a lot in
Persuading people to buy their products.
OK? And then, in cyberspace, you would also see a lot
of this persuasion rule have been used by those social
engineer, OK? Social Yeah, they try to use this
rule in their social engineering techniques and then trick people
to do the wrong thing, OK? So, they will use all these six persuasion rule.
So, this is um to create a psychological influence um
on human, OK? Because human has those nature,
um, and then the persuasion rule were designed around this human nature.
OK. So, these are the six rules. The first one,
reciprocity, which means, um, They ask
you to do something, and they will give you something for return,
OK? I'll give you some reward. And then,
in that way, you would think that request is reasonable,
and you will just, uh, uh, do that, what they have requested.
So we call that reciprocity rule, OK? So,
um, you can see that sometimes we also call that rewarding rule,
OK? Um, And then that's the first one. And the second one is a
commitment rule. So which means you would
like to maintain a consistency in what you have already said
or done or promised before, right? So that's a commitment rule.
The human nature, they, they tend to keep the consistency,
OK? And with what they have promised. So,
that's a commitment rule. Sometimes we also call that consistency,
consistent rule, consistency rule. And the third one is
social proof. The social proof means um if
a uh if Sometimes you would see
uh an, an advertisement saying, especially online,
OK. Internet, internet advertisement saying,
oh, there have been 100 million, uh sorry,
probably, yeah, 1 million people, let's say.
OK, 1 million uh customers use this product and the,
and 97% of them think their skin is a skin product.
The skin has been um uh improved. OK.
So, that's actually using this social proof rule um to
persuade you to believe in their product.
OK? So that's a social proof. And then the liking is to,
for example, some, some skin product. Again,
that's proof skin product. I will invite some uh movie star to,
to, to do the marketing for them, right,
to do the promotion for the product. And then,
that's actually using this liking persuasion rule because you like that
star, and then you think, her skin, her skin is really
nice, and then, and then you just buy the same product as her.
So this is a liking persuasion rule used in sales and marketing,
right? It's the liking persuasion rule. And the authority means
um the people as a, as a human, right? So,
the human nature is to trust and agree with an expert based on
visual, uh, visual, um,
Cues, right? Like some, um, police, police officer,
police officer, sorry, police officer, and,
and some doctor, right? And then they're wearing a suit,
and then they looks like very uh authorized person
to say something, and you tend to trust them.
Right? So that's authority persuasion rule.
And then the scarcity is the last one. so that one
means That one means, um, if
you receive some advertisement saying,
Saying, OK, um, Saying
There's a very limited time of this offer,
and if you don't be quick, you, you miss,
you miss that one and only 500 left, right?
And then, and then it's only available until probably midnight
today. So, and then that's just to create some scarcity,
um, meaning there, right? So, um,
So that's a, that's a scarcity persuasion rule.
And then in cyberspace, you often would get some
phishing email using this persuasion rule to trick you
to click their links, OK? And some examples are here,
right? So these are the six persuasion rules you can see,
right? We have sometimes received an email like
this. And first, let's look at this, OK,
the, the, the one here. The National Criminal History
Check. Um, and it has some logo,
right? And has some signed name, um, looks
like very legitimate, right? National crime check.
And what persuasion rule this phishing email has applied so that
people tend to think, oh, this is probably something true.
And I should click here um to, and then enter this.
Right. So, begin my criminal history check.
So, which persuasion rule has been used
here in this phishing email? Can you type your answer in the chat?
Whether it has used any persuasion rule.
Actually, there's one rule used here, which is authority,
authority. So, authority has been used and because it looks
like from a legitimate officer or office,
right, which is doing this national crime check and,
and it has this logo and looks like very,
um, yeah, legitimate. So, it's an authority rule used
in this phishing email. Um, yeah, so we'd better be
aware of this kind of rule used in phishing email.
Another one here, I will read out the text.
It's hard to, to, to, to see them. It says,
Did you know that you can earn an extra 16 gigabytes of
Dropbox uh space by inviting your friends?
And there's a link to invite your friend.
And every time the friend installs Dropbox,
we'll give both of you 500 megabytes of space for free.
So far, more than 100,000 existing
users and more than 220,000 new users
have received extra space. There are some
persuasion rule used for this phishing email.
So what is that? Can you identify that? Which
persuasion rule have been used in this phishing email?
Of course, the link, um, yeah, probably is not true,
right? So we, we'd better be aware and we'd better be aware some persuasion
rule have been used in this phishing email and we'd better not just click the link,
right? Um, but If we're not aware,
and we might think that it's very reasonable if we just invite our friend,
we'll get some free space, um, as a reward,
right? So here, that reciprocity rule
has been, has been used. And there's another rule has
been used, which is social proof, social proof,
OK? Because it says more than that many user and more than this
new user have been granted those extra space,
right? So, that's a social proof. OK? So,
true persuasion rules have been used in this phishing email and looks so
real, right? Uh, which is actually a social,
um, sorry, phishing email. And then we should be
aware all those 6 persuasion rule can be used by the bad people and
they're doing. The bad thing to trick people
to believe in them, right? And then, of course,
in the, the other side, this persuasion rule can also be used for
good purpose. And here are some example.
Um, when we, when, this is one AGEA example,
they actually Um, use their vocal proponent,
um, culture, OK? And then they would say,
those proponents will change their password regularly.
And 90 of your colleagues don't click attachments from untrusted source,
right? So, and then they're using this statement actually to
utilize this social proof, persuasion rule to
lead people to do the right thing in their company.
Can lead their employee to the right thing.
And then also another, um, another example for that
commitment rule used is to um set up
some acceptable use policy. OK? A lot of big company,
they actually For their employee to sign their
AUP. Why they are forcing their employee to sign this AUP
is they actually are using this commitment rule,
because they believe if you sign on the document,
you become serious of following that document or following what you have signed,
because human nature tends to show the consistency with
what they have promised, right? So, And then that AUP
normally uh would include um some good practice you
should do, you should follow when you are using your email,
and how should you manage your password,
and the, the behavior you should do when you go online,
and what you should be, I mean, paying, pay attention.
Right? So that's a commitment rule used here.
And then the liking rule can be used to lead,
to guide people to follow their leader if they like them,
or some good example set up by the company.
I mean, if they like them, and then they should just uh um probably follow them to
do the right thing. And also, authority rule is used when
the company Uh, set up some regulation and policy and let all
people follow them, right? And then, uh,
be aware of them and then they're using this authority rule to
influence people to do the right thing. OK.
So they are, and they're more uh can be designed around this six persuasion
rule, OK? As a good practice for people to do the right thing.
And then, um, the last part is about um the
mobile device use and internet use. I wish everyone can be
aware of these two, probably, um, The
most popular behavior we would, uh, we would be doing every day,
right? And then, the most popular devices we're using,
right, the mobile phone. And then, we should be aware how many attack
surface each mobile phone has. And uh what are the permission we
have control on the mobile device, and uh how should we control them,
right? So for the mobile device, and we
should know it has more attack surface than the normal laptop
or computer, right? It has so many different
interface. We can use the phone, such as the
NFC one and probably it's not something included in your laptop
or in your computer. Right. NFC is a near field
communication protocol, and when we use our phone to
pay um through those post machine, OK,
in those supermarket, right, when we just tap our phone on the,
on the machine, uh, post machine. And we actually ask through this near
field communication protocol to pay, right,
which is not through Bluetooth or, or Wi Fi,
right? So, it has more interface, definitely.
It has all this SIM card, if we have the,
the extra extendable card, and so on, right?
So they're all Uh, kind of create actual attack
surface, OK, to this phone. And then, for
the phone, it has a lot of function and the sensitive function include these
three types. One is the internet banking and location-based
apps like our GPS, um, map, right? And also,
um, sorry, healthcare. I think it, Uh,
or sometimes we call that healthcare software because it provides
the medical, um, information to access the
patient's profile, right? So, it had these three types of
the, uh, sensitive function and we have to
be aware of, right? And with those three types
of sensitive function, And what we can control is
these 4 types of control. We can sometimes um
grant the full permission and sometimes we can just uh cautiously
probably um not grant that permission, right?
So these are 4 types of permission we can grant or we can control,
right? However, they are through different systems and they
are allowing users to control them. Uh,
at different time. We can grant permission at
either installation time or runtime, which means,
OK? If we. And grant the permission
at the installation time. And then, every time when we use the
app, and we always have that permission,
which were granted at installation time.
And then the iOS, which is iPhone, uh, that,
that system, right? Always gather the permission at runtime,
which means an installation, OK, doesn't care and doesn't ask for the
permission probably to access to your location or to access to your message,
right? It doesn't ask that one. But every time when you run the app,
You were asked to whether you want to give that permission to the location when you
run this app or not, right? So you have that option.
You can either grant the permission at installation time or you just uh grant the permission only
when you're using that app. Run, run the app uh in your mobile device.
Of course, uh, I would say, grant the permission at installation
time, sometimes cause more risks because once we installed and
we, we grant the permission to our location,
when we install that app, and we probably just forget to close that
um permission later, right? If we're not using that one,
and then that permission is always granted,
and then the app. Whether or not running in your mobile device
has access to your app, and maybe would send some location
information behind you or without your awareness,
right, to another remote server. Right. So,
with the installation time um granted permission,
um, a user normally wouldn't probably change it later or,
uh, or maybe turn off that permission later and then which cause more
risks to our mobile phone, right? OK? So,
and also, there's some situation there um we really
don't, um, as a user, don't have that enough information
to make the right choice. So when we don't know whether we should grant the
permission or not, um, we should always turn off the permission.
Right? If that stops us using that app, and then we should
consider whether that app is a really good one,
and should we just use that one. If, without giving it
permission to access to my location and I can't use other function,
whether that location permission really necessary.
If you don't think the location permission is necessary to use their apps,
other function. And you should probably question that app is very,
maybe not a very good one because it probably try to just to track your location.
And force you to agree on their, um, on their
permission request, right? So, it's just the,
um, we, we got to be aware, um, of what permission we're granting
to a particular app. And then there are 4 types of information we
have control as a user. And we should very,
be very cautious when we grant any of them to an
app, OK? When we install that one or when we run that app,
and should we, should we grant that access or not,
right? So, and then, so the first type is the network
communication permission, right? So we can,
we can have the control um to grant the full internet access.
Um, and, and with that one, of course, the
malicious app may send sensitive information from the phone to a malicious server if
a full internet access permission has been granted,
right? And then there's a personal information like the contact data permission,
um, is controllable by a user, right? By a phone
owner, right? And then if we grant a
full internet access to an app. At the same time,
we also grant the contact data uh access
permission to that app, OK? That, what that app can
do is it can send the whole contact
information to a remote server because it has this both permissions,
OK, which have been granted by you to that app.
So if that app is not a very good one, And it can just do this,
right? And then also the message, um,
so normally when we're using the bank app,
we probably will allow the bank app to access to our SMS as a
verification code, right? So the bank can log in or can do the
transaction for you, right? Or, or we can just not allow the bank app
to access to your SMS at all. And then we just type our six digit
code by ourselves because we can read the message and we can then come back to the
bank app to, to type by ourselves. So that's a safer way
actually. If we are concerned about some bank app,
or if we're concerned about the bank app can be compromised by the bad
people, we, we can just stop it. Um. The permission to allow
this bank app to read my uh SMS. OK, I can do that.
I have that control. And if it's not bank app,
it can be some other online shopping um app,
like Amazon or like eBay, right? And
we probably, it's better not allow them to read the message,
to have the access to our SMS. Because of course,
sometimes it saves time for you to, to copy your six digit SMS
and back to your app and to do the login.
Uh, you never know that app can be compromised or not,
right? If it's compromised, it can read all your SMS,
right? And then that means when next time when you,
when you log into a bank account, you will receive a verification code.
And that code can also be readable, OK, by that
Amazon or eBay app. If that app, uh, OK,
some, someone like, um, That app has been compromised
and someone then can also read your bank verification code,
right? So, which is really, really uh not good because
We are not supposed to give our bank verification code to anyone else,
right? However, some app be, because they have access to your SMS and then they
can just read your SMS all the time without your awareness.
And uh if, uh, if we, that app has also full
internet access, and then that Amazon or eBay app can send your
bank verification code to the remote. Server
and the remote server, if there's an attacker there and then they can.
They, they can just log into your bank account if they already have your password,
OK, um, obtained and then they can just use your verification code at this
time and just log into your bank account,
right? So that's what happened in reality.
When, when, when we grant the permission,
we should really be aware what we are granting and should
we just let this app to read our SMS or not.
If we, we think it's safer not to, uh, or we
just don't bother us to. OK, we don't think it's bothering to copy and
paste and just don't grant that. Don't grant that permission at all,
right? And then the location wise, uh, location is
another permission we have control over.
But I'd say if you don't think the location,
uh, I mean, for myself, I actually turn off my location
permission to some of my map, um, GPS
map. Because I only, OK, when I use that one,
I, I allow that one access to my location.
I turn on my location permission every time when I use them.
Once I don't use them, I do not allow that app to track
my location. OK. So, but for you and
sometimes some online social media app, they also track your location.
It's not necessary. You don't have to grant their permission.
Uh, grant them your permission and to track your location.
Why? It's not necessary, right? So, we can turn off those
location, uh, permission. For our goodness,
for our goodness, right? So, for our privacy.
Um, and, OK, so that's the 4th type of permission we should be aware
of and we have control over. We should always be cautious when we grant any permission.
And one last page about the internet use,
right? So this is often something people are not aware of,
right? And then that's why I'm, I'm putting this one and which is also
very critical one. And we have also some um
anti-cybersquating Consumer Protection Act to prevent this
URL hijacking. What this means is when you log
into, uh, when you go to some website and you type your URL link,
uh, wrongly, and then it can, these are what can happen,
right? Which really, really, um, are not something you
wish to have, have happened, right, to your computer.
And then so these are hijacking, which, um,
when we have, when we heard different names like direct linking,
cybersquatting, sting, cybersquat, I'm sorry,
typosquatting, cybersquatting, they all mean the same thing,
URL hijacking. The fake URL and brandjacking.
So these names all mean the same thing. Basically,
it's just a typo in your URL link, or sometimes you put a
different extension, like Google.net. OK?
Do not just try that one because you don't know what,
what's in that site. Cause it, it's just uh wish people can type wrong,
right? And uh it just wait there and for you to go to their website without even
clicking any links on that alternate website and your computer
may get hacked, OK? Get some uh malware
attached. OK. And sometimes there's a hyphen and you
forgot, uh, and sometimes a different spelling and you
just, uh, do not pay attention, and then you will be directed to a wrong place.
And then that can All this bad thing could happen to you,
right? So, which is why there are some um good
practice we should follow. Uh, we should always use a trusted or we are sure
about the website and then, then we go, OK,
we return, uh, enter and go, right? If we don't know,
and we should always use um Google to search for the right one
because everyone probably won't make wrong um to go to Google,
right? And just use Google to search the right name of the official
um URL of a website. And then,
and then use a different computer in a different VLAN.
So, VLAN is a virtual, virtual, a virtual local area
network. Virtual local network, um, local area network.
Actually, um, Will, will restrict some malware if
it has been downloaded by a computer. We'll just restrict that malware
to spread within that virtual land, OK, virtual local area network
will not spread quickly to, to a different VLAN.
So that's some networking technique which to prevent the faster spreading of the
malware, OK, which is why when we are doing launch surfing,
lunchtime web surfing, And we can just use a different computer in a different
VLAN um to protect. Because when we're going web surfing,
if we got URL hijacking happened to my computer,
at least this computer is affected but not the working computer in a
different VLAN, right? Different virtual land.
OK? And then, so also never click the link.
And if we own a domain, which means if we are a
business provider and we own the domain,
we should also register the typo before attacker because that protect
our customer. And uh if they make some um unconscious
mistake, and then they won't, OK, go to some
really, um, Bad one and get some
ransomware or malware installed in their computer,
in your customer's computer, right? So, these are all because of URL
hijack hijacking. And if you hear all these names,
you know what's, what does that mean and also for yourself.
When you are not sure what is the web link,
OK, URL name for your website, and you should always
search for the official one. Do not just type by yourself,
because by typing wrongly, and you might get URL hijack
hijacked, OK? A very important part. So,
finally, with the cyber uh security awareness improvement,
as an officer, and what we should do is to teach
what is the security, but not how of the security.
That's some definition from America's um national,
um, I mean, N um Association. So, they're managing the whole
cybersecurity side of thing. Um, so they have a lot of standard as
well, right? So, Um, as a cybersecurity officer,
and we should teach people and we should improve people's awareness,
right? And then we should be aware why the email and
web-based attacks always be successful, and these are the reasons.
And we can use this as a, as a very good guideline to
make an improvement plan. OK. So we
should know, um, no AUP poli policy is a reason
why people sometimes make mistake because there's no acceptable user,
um, policy, mm, and then not set up and then people
haven't signed and people don't follow and people are not aware what are the right
thing to do. OK? So AUP normally would include everything,
um, the people should follow when they go online.
Right? And also, there's no proper cyber awareness training.
So now, I think many companies they actually run this cyber awareness training,
uh, in their company. They actually, uh,
provide a lot of Google, um, phishing email photo so that
the people are, are aware of these are phishing emails,
and this can happen through this or that.
And then these six persuasion rules are there.
And then, Everyone should be aware of them,
of them, and then should not click any links in those phishing emails.
OK. And then maybe there's no buy-in from employees and then
that's an issue and people should, um, OK,
the and security officer, you should let them know,
and this is for all's benefit, right? And then people have buy-in in this domain
and then they should do the right thing.
And also with the, with the email service and
HTTP those uh poor security are not aware about,
by, by, by people, right? And then there's a poor
endpoint protection. For example, um, people don't um
protect their device very well, OK? And then the people also bring your
own device like their mobile device and go to the same Wi Fi.
And go to the same um local network. And then,
Those devices were not properly protected.
And then those antivirus and anti-spa um to their email service
and antivirus software were not properly installed or updated,
right? So, um, these are the reasons. So when we do a
cyber improvement awareness plan, uh, as a security officer,
maybe that's your job in, in the future,
right, in this domain. And then probably you got to think about,
to make a good plan and you can use this one as a guideline to improve the
awareness. OK? So, that's actually all today.
Um, sorry to go over a few minutes. And if you have any question,
um, yeah, please text me, uh, in chat, or you can always,
uh, Uh, approach me through Teams. I'm, uh,
constantly I check the messages there. OK.
Um, if not, uh, please feel free to leave.
I don't think the concepts here in this week is easy,
uh, sorry, it's hard to to, it's hard to understand,
OK? So that's fine. And if you don't have any question,
but anytime later, if you have any question,
please let me know. OK? Thank you. Thank you,
everyone. Bye.